<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architecture and Urban Design | Aseem Deodhar</title>
    <link>/tag/architecture-and-urban-design/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/architecture-and-urban-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Architecture and Urban Design</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Aseem Deodhar © 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/static/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>Architecture and Urban Design</title>
      <link>/tag/architecture-and-urban-design/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Urban Design</title>
      <link>/project/chhatra_ud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/chhatra_ud/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;an-introduction-to-urban-design&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;An Introduction to Urban Design&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was published in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chhatraprabodhan.org/&#34;&gt;Chhatra Prabodhan magazine&lt;/a&gt;, in their annual &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1svsSvNmnXp7xvEc-fkuFtYJgy2SRaTYr/view&#34;&gt;Diwali Special - 2019&lt;/a&gt; issue. Chhatra Prabodhan is a monthly magazine published from Pune, India aimed at school-aged kids in the states of Maharashtra, Goa, and Gujarat. Three versions of the magazine - one in English, one in Marathi, and a third one aimed at rural school-age kids are published monthly. The goal is to expose children to ideas and knowledge in a fun, informative way as a supplement to what they learn in school.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered who decides how the chairs we sit on, houses we live in, or the clothes we wear are made, or look like? These people are called designers, and they don’t stop at chairs, houses or roads. Designers are everywhere! Furniture, cutlery, electronics, your favorite TV shows and movies, books, cars, apps on mobile phones, bicycles, shoes, parks, streets, footpaths, the list is endless.
In the list above, I design parks, streets, and footpaths! People who design streets, footpaths, parks, and other public spaces are called Urban Designers. Think about what Urban Design might mean. Can you think of other places and things which an ‘Urban Designer’ may design?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine yourself in the role of an urban designer. Is there a busy intersection near your house or school? Go stand near it and observe a few things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether there is a traffic signal, how many people are actually following the rules? Do you think there are too many cars and two-wheelers? Are they taking up most of the road’s width? How much space is available for pedestrians and bicyclists? Do you think the space they have left is enough and safe? As a matter of principle remember that the goal of our roads is to move people and not vehicles. See the picture below. This is a very popular image which you may have seen before. See how much space is required to transport the same number of people in 3 different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/project/chhatra_ud/carbikebus.jpg&#34; title=&#34;City of Munster - Vehicle and Space Demonstration&#34; alt=&#34;City of Munster - Vehicle and Space Demonstration&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;City of Munster - Vehicle and Space Demonstration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be great if the leftover space could be used for a playground, or a fountain, or some trees? So, do you think its best if we all had one car for every one of us, or if we all used either busses or our bicycles to get where we want?
Let us go back to our intersection, the busy one with too many polluting cars and two-wheelers. Imagine if there is enough space for people to walk and ride their bicycles without getting afraid of a car or bus going over them. There is also enough space for the vegetable and fruit vendors to sell their vegetables and fruits. It will be far away from all the pollution, and your parents will also be happy to know that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you think you would improve what you see before you? What do you think is the main purpose of a road? Is it to transport cars, or to transport people? A road or street can also become a public space where people go for their evening walks, children learn how to ride their first bicycle, your grandparents sit on a bench and meet their friends, you go for a jog, office-goers sit and have their lunch break. In fact, if you see all the activities above, realize that these also work in a park! So why can’t our streets also become like parks? Just that they’ll become parks through which you go to different places: A big network of parks connecting your house to your school, to the local market, or the mall, or even to your parent’s office. I will leave you here with another image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/project/chhatra_ud/beforeafterroads.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Sourced from NACTO&#34; alt=&#34;Sourced from NACTO&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Sourced from NACTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the same street which the urban designer has redesigned with some changes. Can you identify what the differences are? Which one do you prefer? Which street do you think pedestrians and bicyclists would feel most safe on? Where would a vegetable vendor would feel safe sitting?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a street in Bangalore called St Mark’s road. The designers decided to reduce the width of the carriageway (the part of the road intended for vehicles) by half. This meant that pedestrians and cyclists got nearly 6 metres of footpath space! There was definitely a huge public outcry over this. Newspapers and TV channels blasted the designers and executers over this decision. But today? Car movement is smooth, senior citizens can easily walk, children from nearby schools are seen running and playing on these ‘street playgrounds’, cyclists can easily get around; all without getting scared of being run over by cars. What is the role of a public space do you think? Is it to make its users, that is people, more comfortable, or just be a pipe through which cars go from A to B?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think Urban Design is important for our cities? India is going through a lot of changes, and you are growing up with those changes happening all around you. Making sure that the cities and towns you live in are healthy and fun is a very important and difficult task, which will definitely become even more important as you grow up and finish school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Design Portfolio</title>
      <link>/project/jana_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/jana_work/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;The Professional Design Portfolio contains curated design documentation of two major projects completed between 2016 and 2018. Both projects contain elements relevant to the study of urban space, and the human interactions that create these spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please click on the &lt;em&gt;slides&lt;/em&gt; button above or &lt;a href=&#34;/slides/jana/#/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to see the portfolio pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specifications for Urban Roads Execution Phases 1 &amp;amp; 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tender S.U.R.E. | Jana USP | 2016 - present&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tender S.U.R.E. are the first set of guidelines in India concieved by Jana Urban Space Foundation for urban road design redevelopment and procurement for execution. The Tender S.U.R.E. standards aim in making the road more durable, ease pedestrian movement, ensure free flow of traffic and avoid unnecessary road cuttings by various utility agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upgradation and Redevelopment of A Historic Economic Centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krishna Rajendra Market | Jana USP | 2017 - present&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KR (Krishna Rajendra) Market in Bangalore is a historic public market dating back to the early 1920s. Since then it has transformed from a small neighborhood market to the largest supplier of fruits, vegetables, meat, and other sundry items to Bangalore; a city of 11 million people and growing. Although KR Market is the largest market in the city in terms of volume and value of commodities exchanged, it faces a number of issues that deter it from living up to its full potential. Today it is noted as a major flower market as well as an iconic Bangalorean institution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate Design Portfolio</title>
      <link>/project/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/thesis/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;The Undergraduate Portfolio contains curated design documentation of three key projects completed between 2014 and 2016. All three projects contain elements relevant to the study of urban space, and the human interactions that create these spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please click on the &lt;em&gt;slides&lt;/em&gt; button above or &lt;a href=&#34;/slides/archi_portfolio/#/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to see the portfolio pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Civic Institutions as Catalysts for Urban Rejuvenation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thesis | Year 5 Semester 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project eveolved out of a need to establish cultural institutions while simultaneously addressing issues of urban decay and irregular land utilisation. The development of an active public space was acheived through design interventions which are human in scale
and proportion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a need therefore for the development of an active public space which could complement the existing pedestrian plaza of MG Marg for urban rejuvenation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sakaalnagar - Residential Redevelopment &amp;amp; Upgradation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mass Housing | Year 4 Semester 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sakaalnagar is a 30 year old housing complex in Pune built when construction materials available were of poor quality. A proposal to redevelop it was finalized in 2013, and our studio took it up as an academic project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design philosophy stems from Eyes on the Streets, and Liveable Neighbourhoods concepts aiming to reduce social distances and increase social cohesion and the idea of shared security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separate pedestrian and vehicular corridors ensures the safety of residents, playing children and the vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questioning Urban Paradigms - Studying the Changing Face of Tulshibaug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Dissertation | Year 4 Semester 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research aims at understanding the reason for the development of the urban areas of Tulshibaug and Mandai. The architecture and urban patterns of a particular era are a reflection of the social, cultural, economic and political situation prevalent at that time. This has often resulted in an entire city’s character being changed or even the cultural attitudes of its people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this study is to understand the reasons for this situation, both historical and current.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It aims at evolving certain design andd policy solutions to improve the present day situation by understanding the needs of all stakeholders including but not limited to shoppers, tourists, worshippers, shopkeepers, and residents.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
